Debadutta Sahoo

UI/UX Designer

- Charlotte, NC
- **1** 704-575-7238
- debaduttabehera45
 6@gmail.com

✓—— Skills ——

- Visual Design
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- User Flows
- Style Guide
- Web Design
- Mobile Design
- Responsive Design



- Sketch
- Invision
- Marvel
- Flinto
- Balsamiq
- Draw.io
- Photoshop

<— Research — ▶

- Competitive analysis
- User stories
- Personas
- User flows
- Usability testing

- Scrum
- Agile
- Jira
- ▶ HP ALM
- Java and Selenium
- ▶ HTML, CSS, Java Script

✓—— Office Tools ——▶

- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel
- Power Point

https://deedee135.github.io/Debadutta.Sahoo-portfolio/

Passionate UI/UX designer with 3+ years of experience in quality and business analysis. Skilled at creating visually attractive and thoughtful interfaces based on principles of design, and has strong visual design sense with knowledge of current web design trends and techniques, i.e. HTML/CSS. Demonstrate the ability to present and explain design decisions to team members and stakeholders.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance UI/UX Designer

April 2020 - Present

- Design UI from inception to final product and successfully launched brand new **MeetMonk** Inc website and other internal pages.
- Design mockups for website layout and create final web assets.
- Work closely with the product owner to design pixel-perfect responsive designs.
- Create visual prototypes that demonstrate new concepts and features.

Business Analyst

TIAA-CREF, Charlotte, North carolina

April 2019 - Dec 2019

- Analyzed the web services and derived user stories from functional requirements.
- Created/updated projects, user stories, and tracked progress and all relevant work in JIRA.
- Worked in SCRUM environment and attended daily SCRUM meeting, sprint planning.

UAT Expert

LPL Financial, Fort Mill, South carolina

March 2018 - February 2019

- Developed and executed test plans to ensure the accurate development of complex system from a business and functional perspective.
- Wrote test cases and executed in ALM. Prepared daily execution and defect Reports of UAT testing phase.

QA Analyst

Fusion Informatics, USA

February 2017 - February 2018

- Executed the test cases, identified defects, classified and raised defects, participated in defect triages.
- Demonstrated understanding of the concepts of unit testing, smoke testing, integration testing, system testing, and regression testing

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry 2019 - 2020

Certified UI Designer

QSpider 2017

Java and Selenium Certification

Frameboxx Animation, India 2010

SOA University, India 2005 -2009

Bachelor in Computer Science